Guide to the Linda Willing Collection on Women in the Fire Service WAG.375
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Linda Willing Collection on Women in the Fire Service
1982-1997
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Willing, Linda F.
WAG.375
1 linear foot in 2 manuscript boxes
Linda Willing is a retired career fire officer who formerly worked with the Boulder Colorado Fire Department. In 1982, she co-founded the organization Women in the Fire Service (WFS). Following her career as a fire officer, Willing established Real World Training and Consulting, a company through which Willing works with emergency services agencies on leadership development and diversity management. The Linda Willing Collection on Women in the Fire Service (dated 1982-1997) consists of materials collected by Willing documenting her career as a fire officer and her engagement with Women in the Fire Service (WFS). Materials in this collection include correspondence, conference programs and ephemera, newspaper articles, and newsletters. The collection also includes materials documenting organizing work to establish and further occupational health and safety protections for women fire officers. Maternity leave policies and sexual harassment are particularly well documented.
Scope and Contents
The Linda Willing Collection on Women in the Fire Service (dated 1982-1997) consists of materials collected by Willing documenting her career as a fire officer and her engagement with Women in the Fire Service (WFS). Materials in this collection include correspondence, conference programs and ephemera, newspaper articles, and newsletters. The collection also includes materials documenting organizing work to establish and further occupational health and safety protections for women fire officers. Maternity leave policies and sexual harassment are particularly well documented.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Linda Willing in July 2023; the accession number associated with this gift is 2023.074.
Biographical Note
Linda Willing is a retired career fire officer who formerly worked with the Boulder Colorado Fire Department. In 1982, she co-founded the organization Women in the Fire Service (WFS). Following her career as a fire officer, Willing established Real World Training and Consulting, a company through which Willing works with emergency services agencies on leadership development and diversity management. She published On the Line: Women Firefighters Tell Their Stories (2011), and worked as an adjunct instructor and curriculum advisor with the National Fire Academy. Willing graduated with a bachelor's degree in American Studies from the University of Pennsylvania, a master's degree in organization development from Regis University. She is also a certified mediator.
Women fire fighters -- United States.; Women -- Employment -- United States.; Sex discrimination in employment.; Maternity leave; Willing, Linda F.; Women in the Fire Service (Organization)
- California Women in the Fire Service, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Conferences, 1985-2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- FDNY Women, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Human Relations Manuals, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Maternity Leave -- General, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Maternity Policies, 1985-2005 (Box 1, Folder 8-10, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Maternity Survey, 1983-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
- News Articles, 1998-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Parental Leave, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- Sexual Harassment, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Women in the Fire Service -- General, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- USFA Project (Pregnancy, 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)